<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luke Griffith</title>
    <link>https://lukemgriffith.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Luke Griffith</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:59:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lukemgriffith.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Code</title>
      <link>https://lukemgriffith.github.io/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemgriffith.github.io/code/</guid>
      <description>Opensource Contributions cChoco/cChocoFeature At work we had a need to set chocolatey features via DSC, so we could roll out configuration changes to our clients. I developed this resource in our branched version of cChoco and worked with Chocolatey Software to merge our newly developed resource back in to the community project.
Link to merge: 5b57ef4
Personal Projects ShowTruthTable During the first year of university I came across a number of logic problems in revision and exams, to give me an easy way to check my work and improve my Python I created a dynamic truth table generator that outputs to the console the result of the python expresson entered into a REPL loop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://lukemgriffith.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemgriffith.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Luke is a passionate and highly focused individual, dedicated to learning about technology and its implementation. With over 7 years of IT experience working with business critical infrastructure, and applications. His primary skills set is around infrastructure and os, automation and configuration.
He has a long background supporting and engineering Windows based solutions, but is familiar and comfortable with Linux.
He has a keen interest in software development, CI/CD, reusable software design and enjoys building platforms and designing frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://lukemgriffith.github.io/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemgriffith.github.io/blog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>